# **Harry Johnston**

- Bristol
- ☑ virtual.slide@gmail.com
- **\** 07903686825
- www.harry-johnston.com
- Harry-Johnston
- in Harry Johnston

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

## Certified Scrum-Master

Scrum Alliance

## **Rock Climbing Instructor**

Mountain Training

#### **INTERESTS**

I've been a climber for almost a decade; I competed during university but have since found a lot of fulfilment in achieving personal goals. I love trekking and have hiked the Pacific Crest Trail from Canada to Mexico. I'm an enthusiastic but untalented surfer, I play in a weekly D&D session and I love drum and bass.

## **Full-Stack Web Developer**

I am a full-stack developer who loves finding solutions to both micro and macro problems, soon to graduate from iO Academy's Full-Stack course. My education and recent career have been engineering focused and I have been excited applying these skills in the tech world. I love spending my time in the hills and mountains as I have been an avid climber for nearly a decade.

# **PROJECTS**

I have worked on projects from within a scrum team as well as individually. Below are a small selection of my favourites, if you'd like to see more please have a look at my portfolio.

## Icepace

OOP Social Media App

An Object-Oriented PHP project where we built out a full-stack social media app within a scrum team. Using a MySQL database to feed the back-end, we applied SOLID principles, and I built input a validator & sanitiser among other things. The site's front-end was constructed using SASS to enable mixins, nesting and CSS variables.

## GitHub|Live Version

## Igloo Inbox

React Email Client

Utilising React to consume a pre-built API, we built an email client based on a given wireframe. We used Bootstrap to ensure consistency with the wireframe and the app made use of AJAX to pull from the API. The app was built as part of an agile team where I took on Scrum Master responsibilities as well as being a developer.

GitHub|Live Version

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## **Hoare Lea**

(Aug 2019 - Jul 2022)

Consultant Engineer

I worked as a consultant MEP engineer, designing mechanical systems for residential and commercial buildings. My projects spanned from a few days to a year and a half which taught me time and resource management skills. I line-managed and taught Junior Engineers, as well as co-ordinating with multi-disciplinary design teams. I also led a number of successful small to medium sized projects - a responsibility usually reserved for a Senior Engineer.

#### L'Oréal

(Feb 2018 - Jul 2019)

Supply Chain Graduate

As part of L'Oréal's Supply Chain Graduate program, I worked across a few different areas of the business from a distribution centre to head office. I took the initiative to teach myself VBA and SQL and introduced a number of tools that removed 10+ hours a week of recurring work. I forecasted demand on the ~£30 million Men's Skincare category - the first time a graduate was allowed to do this.

## **EDUCATION**

## iO Academy

(Jul 2022 - Oct 2022)

Full-Stack Bootcamp

# Cardiff University

(Aug 2013 - Jun 2017)

Mechanical Engineering, First Class Masters (4-years)

- Took all 3 elective computing modules where we learnt computing fundamentals & Object Oriented C++
- Studied Pure Mathematics using MATLAB

## **Rugby School**

(Aug 2008 - Jun 2013)

Maths, Physics, History